<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
  contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
  this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
  The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
  (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
  the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE document [
  <!ENTITY project SYSTEM "project.xml">
]>
<document url="introduction.html">

    &project;

    <properties>
        <author email="rslifka@sfu.ca">Robert Slifka</author>
        <title>Introduction</title>
    </properties>

<body>

<section name="Table of Contents">
<toc/>
</section>

<section name="소개">

<p>관리자와 웹개발자분들이 톰캣에 익숙해지기전 알아야 할 몇몇 중요한 정보들을 포함하고 있습니다. 이 문서는 
톰캣 컨테이너가 가지고 있는 개념과 전문용어에 대해서 설명합니다. 또한, 여러분들이 필요한 정보를 얻으려고 할 때 참고해야 할 
문서를 소개합니다. 
</p>

</section>


<section name="전문용어">

<p>이 문서를 읽는 동안 여러분은 여러 전문용어를 접하게 될 것입니다. 이 중 일부분은 톰캣에 특정한 용어들입니다.
다른 용어들은 
<a href="http://wiki.apache.org/tomcat/Specifications"> 서블렛과 JSP 명세서에 정의되어 있습니다.</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Context</strong> - In a nutshell, a Context is a
    web application.</li>
<li><strong>Term2</strong> - This is it.</li>
<li><strong>Term3</strong> - This is it!</li>
</ul>

</section>


<section name="디렉토리와 파일들">

<p>이 문서를 통해서 여러분은 <strong>$CATALINA_HOME</strong>가 많이 언급되는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
이는 여러분의 톰캣 설치경로의 루트를 뜻합니다. 우리가 "이 정보는 여러분의 $CATALINA_HOME/README.txt 파일에서 찾을 수 있습니다"
라고 한다는 것은 README.txt 파일이 여러분의 톰캣 설치경로의 루트에 있다는 것을 뜻합니다. 선택적으로 각각 인스턴스에
<strong>$CATALINA_BASE</strong>을 설정하면서 많은 인스턴스를 만들 수 있습니다.만약 많은 인스턴스를 만들지 않으면 <strong>$CATALINA_BASE</strong>
은 <strong>$CATALINA_HOME</strong>과 같습니다.</p>

<p>이들은 몇몇 톰캣의 중요한 디렉토리 들입니다:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>/bin</strong> - 시작, 종료, 그리고 다른 스크립트들. (유닉스 시스템을 위한) <code>*.sh</code> 파일들은 (윈도우 시스템을 위한)
<code>*.bat</code> 파일들의 기능적 복사물 입니다. 윈32 커맨드 라인이 몇명 특정 기능을 가지고 있지 않으므로 몇몇 추가적인
파일들이 이 곳에 있습니다.
</li>
<li><strong>/conf</strong> - 설정 파일 및 그와 연관된 DTD 파일들. 이 곳에 있는 가장 중요한 파일은 server.xml 입니다. 
이는 컨테이너를 위한 주요 설정 파일입니다.
</li>
<li><strong>/logs</strong> - 기본적으로 로그 파일들이 이곳에 있습니다.</li>
<li><strong>/webapps</strong> - 이곳은 여러분의 webapps가 가는 곳입니다.</li>
</ul>

</section>


<section name="톰캣 설정하기">

<p>이 센션에서는 컨테이너를 설정하는 동안 필요한 기초 정보를 얻으실 수 있습니다.</p>

<p>설정 파일에 있는 모든 정보들은 톰캣이 시작할 때 사용됩니다. 이는 이 파일들에 대한 어떠한 변경도 컨테이너가 재시작할 때
필요하다는 것을 뜻합니다.
</p>

</section>


<section name="Where to Go for Help">

<p>While we've done our best to ensure that these documents are clearly
written and easy to understand, we may have missed something.  Provided
below are various web sites and mailing lists in case you get stuck.</p>

<p>As Tomcat 7 is a new release of Tomcat, keep in mind that some of the
issues and solutions vary between the major versions of Tomcat (6.x versus
7.x).  As you search around the web, there will be some documentation that
is not relevant to Tomcat 7, but 6.x, 5.x or earlier versions.  Doing 3.x
or 4.x things to 7 will probably not work in most cases as the server.xml
files are very different.</p>

<ul>
<li>Current document - most documents will list potential hangups. Be sure
    to fully read the relevant documentation as it will save you much time
    and effort. There's nothing like scouring the web only to find out that
    the answer was right in front of you all along!</li>
<li><a href="http://wiki.apache.org/tomcat/FAQ">Tomcat FAQ</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wiki.apache.org/tomcat/">Tomcat WIKI</a></li>
<li>Tomcat FAQ at <a href="http://www.jguru.com/faq/home.jsp?topic=Tomcat">jGuru</a></li>
<li>Tomcat mailing list archives - numerous sites archive the Tomcat mailing
    lists. Since the links change over time, clicking here will search
    <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=tomcat+mailing+list+archives">Google</a>.
    </li>
<li>The TOMCAT-USER mailing list, which you can subscribe to
    <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/lists.html">here</a>. If you don't
    get a reply, then there's a good chance that your question was probably
    answered in the list archives or one of the FAQs.  Although questions
    about web application development in general are sometimes asked and
    answered, please focus your questions on Tomcat-specific issues.</li>
<li>The TOMCAT-DEV mailing list, which you can subscribe to
    <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/lists.html">here</a>.  This list is
    <strong>reserved</strong> for discussions about the development of Tomcat
    itself.  Questions about Tomcat configuration, and the problems you run
    into while developing and running applications, will normally be more
    appropriate on the TOMCAT-USER list instead.</li>
</ul>

<p>And, if you think something should be in the docs, by all means let us know
on the TOMCAT-DEV list.</p>

</section>

</body>

</document>
